我们已经谈过如何描述位置和方向，一个人的姿势
We’ve talked about how we can describe the position and orientation, the pose of one
相对于另一个坐标框架。在这里，我们有两个标记的坐标框架
coordinate frame with respect to another. Here, we have two coordinate frames labeled
A和B，我们在这里使用这个符号来表示B相对于A的姿势。我已经介绍过了
A and B, and we use this symbol here to denote the pose of B with respect to A. I've introduced
点P和我可以用两个向量来描述它。我可以用协调来描述它
a point P and I can describe it by two vectors. I can describe it with respect to coordinate
框架A;那是蓝色箭头，或者是坐标框架B;那个红色的箭头。
frame A; that's the blue arrow, or with respect to coordinate frame B; that the red arrow.
我可以使用相对于帧B将关于帧A的矢量与矢量相关联
I can relate the vector with respect to frame A to the vector with respect to frame B using
姿势和这个操作符，点。
the pose and this operator, the dot.
现在，让我们考虑引入另一个坐标系，坐标系C和I.
Now, let's consider that I introduce another coordinate frame, coordinate frame C and I
有一个相对于B描述C的姿势。我可以描述这一点
have a relative pose that describes C with respect to B. And I can describe the point
P相对于坐标系C的矢量。因此，这些相对姿势可以复合
P in terms of a vector with respect to coordinate frame C. So, these relative poses can be compounded
或者组成，所以我可以首先到达姿势B，然后到达姿势C.
or composed, so I can get to the pose C by first of all getting to the pose B and then
走向姿势C.所以，有一些方法可以将这两个姿势加在一起，但是
getting to the pose C. So, there's some way that I can add these two poses together, but
我们还没有准确描述一个姿势是什么。我将介绍另一个摘要
we haven't described yet exactly what a pose is. I'm going to introduce another abstract
运营商。这是一个圆圈内的加号，我打算称之为O+。所以，O+运算符
operator. It is a plus sign inside a circle, I'm going to call that O+. So, the O+ operator
允许我们加入或添加这两个姿势。所以，从帧A到帧的相对姿势
allows us to join or add these two poses. So, the relative pose from frame A to frame
B，O+从帧B到帧C的相对姿势给出了C相对的相对姿态
B, O+ the relative pose from frame B to frame C gives us the relative pose of C with respect
到A.这个O+运算符执行所谓的组合。它允许我们组成，复合，
to A. This O+ operator performs what is called composition. It allows us to compose, to compound,
用引号添加两个姿势。然后，我可以使用我的点运算符进行转换
to add, in inverted commas, two poses together. Then, I can use my dot operator to transform
从帧C到帧A的向量，我们可以无限延长这种方法。我可以
the vector from frame C to frame A, and we can extend this approach indefinitely. I can
复合尽可能多的相对姿势。
compound as many relative poses as I wish.
当我们谈论相对运动之类的事情时，记住这一点非常重要
When we talk about things like relative motions, it's really important to keep in mind that
你应用它们的顺序至关重要。现在，考虑一下这里的例子
the order in which you apply them is critically important. Now, consider the example where
我从参考框架移动，并在x中移动一个30厘米的坐标框架
I move from the reference frame and I move a coordinate frame 30 centimetres in the x
方向，然后我旋转45度，我们定义旋转的约定;
direction and then I rotate it by 45 degrees, and we defined the convention for rotation;
这是45度的正旋转。现在，想象一下我在做这些操作
this is a positive rotation of 45 degrees. Now, imagine that I do these operations in
相反的顺序。所以，我采用我的参考坐标框架，并将其旋转45度
the reverse order. So, I take my reference coordinate frame and I rotate it by 45 degrees
然后我在x方向上翻译30厘米。所以，现在我最终得到了
and then I translate it by 30 centimetres in the x direction. So, now I end up with
这里有一个坐标框架。所以，你看到通过改变我申请的顺序
a coordinate frame over here. So, you see that by changing the order in which I apply
这些基本动作，翻译和旋转，我最终都有很大不同
these elementary motions, the translation and the rotation, I end up with very different
坐标框架。订购非常重要。
coordinate frames. Ordering is really important.
让我们看一个更复杂的例子，我在这里介绍了一个世界坐标框架。
Let's look at a more complex example, and I've introduced here a world coordinate frame.
现在，我介绍一个坐标框架，它表示我的机器人在桌子上的姿势。
Now, I introduce a coordinate frame which represents the pose of my robot on the table.
这是一个坐标框架，代表小机器人的姿势。这是
And here's a coordinate frame which represents the pose of the little robot. And here is
另一个坐标框架，代表大机器人的手。我可以形容
another coordinate frame which represents the hand of the big robot. And I can describe
机器人手的姿势与机器人本身的关系。我可以介绍另一个
the pose of the hand of the robot with respect to the robot itself. I can introduce another
坐标框，描述正在查看这两者的相机的姿势
coordinate frame which describes the pose of a camera which is looking at both of these
机器人。而且，我也许可以根据我的世界坐标来描述相机的姿势
robots. And, I can perhaps describe the pose of the camera with respect to my world coordinate
帧。也许相机能够分辨机器人的位置，相对于相机而言
frame. And perhaps the camera is able to tell where the robot is, with respect to the camera's
坐标框架。而且，也许相机也可以告诉我小机器人的姿势
coordinate frame. And, perhaps the camera can also tell me the pose of the little robot
相对于相机的坐标系。现在，我可能有兴趣知道，
with respect to the camera's coordinate frame. And now, I might be interested in knowing,
这个小机器人相对于大机器人的姿势是什么？或者我可能想知道
what's the pose of the little robot with respect to the big robot? Or I might want to know
是的，从大机器人的手到小机器人的相对姿势是什么，万一
is, what's the relative pose from the hand of the big robot to the little robot, in case
这个大机器人想触摸这个小机器人？或者，也许我可能想知道，是什么
the big robot wanted to touch the little robot? Or, perhaps I might want to know, what's the
关于世界坐标框架的大机器人手的姿势？我已经介绍过了
pose of the hand of the big robot with respect to the world coordinate frame? I've introduced
而是很多坐标框架和相对姿势。我们可以通过介绍来简化这个
rather a lot of coordinate frames and relative poses. We can simplify this by introducing
我称之为姿势图。所以，我保持相同的颜色编码，我保持不变
what I call a pose graph. So, I’ve kept the same colour coding and I kept the same
标签。
labeling.
现在，我不是通过二维坐标系表示姿势，而是简单地用它表示
Now, instead of representing a pose by a two-dimensional coordinate frame, I represent it simply by
一张光盘。连接光盘的线代表相对姿势并注意到它们
a disc. The lines that join the discs represent the relative poses and notice that they are
带箭头的线条，所以这个东西是有向图。实线代表相对
lines with an arrow so this thing is a directed graph. The solid lines represent relative
我们知道的姿势和虚线代表我们不知道的姿势，但也许我们可以
poses that we know and the dashed lines represent poses that we don't know, but perhaps we can
计算它们。
compute them.
所以，让我们在这里强调这个特殊的相对姿势，并说我想确定
So, let's highlight this particular relative pose here and say I want to determine the
这个特定相对姿势的价值。我怎么做？好吧，我们要做什么
value of this particular relative pose. How do I do that? Well, what we’re going to
要做的是遵循一条路径，该路径具有相同的起点和相同的结尾
do is to follow a path through the graph that's got the same starting point and the same ending
点。旅程的第一站是这里的箭头，然后我从姿势C走向姿势
point. The first leg of the journey is this arrow here, and then I go from pose C to pose
R然后去摆姿势H.我们可以说这个相对姿势等于构图
R and then go to pose H. We can say then that this relative pose is equal to the composition
这些其他3个相对姿势。如果我加入这个，这个，这一起让我得到了
of these other 3 relative poses. If I join this, this, and this together it gets me to
姿势图中的相同位置。所以，这是一种我可以计算未知的方法
the same place in the pose graph as this. So, this is a way I can compute an unknown
我所知道的相对姿势的相对姿势。
relative pose in terms of relative poses that I know.
我们来看一个更复杂的例子。现在，我想知道这个相对的姿势：在哪里
Let's have a look at a more complex example. Now, I want to know this relative pose: where
是关于大机器人之手的小机器人。同样的规则。我想要
is the little robot with respect to the hand of the big robot. Same rule again. I want
找到通过这个图表的另一条路径，从H到L。我的第一站
to find another path through this graph that takes me from H to L. The first leg of the
旅程将成为这一次。但在这种情况下，我们需要沿着这个箭头倒退，
journey is going to be this one. But in this case we need to go backwards along this arrow,
所以我把它涂成了红色，表明我正沿着这个特殊的方向前进
so I've coloured it in red to indicate that I'm going backwards along this particular
图的一部分。然后我将沿着图的这一部分向后走，然后我就是
part of the graph. Then I'm going to go backwards along this part of the graph and then I'm
沿着图的这一部分前进。而现在，当我写作
going to go in the forward direction along this part of the graph. And now, when I write
姿势表达式，我引入了两个新符号。这是圆圈内的减号
the pose expression, I've introduced two new symbols. It's a minus sign inside a circle
我将把这个运算符称为O-。所以，对于相对姿势的情况
and I'm going to refer to this operator as O-. So, for the case of the relative poses
用红色编码，我们沿着箭头向后移动，我已经为这个姿势加了前缀
that are coded in red, where we went backwards along the arrow, I've prefixed that pose by
一个减号，因为我走向了相反的方向。虽然这个在这里，但我已经习惯了
a minus sign because I've gone in the reverse direction. Whereas this one here, I've used
O+操作符，因为我沿着箭头向前移动。所以，这是一种方式
the O+ operator because I'm going in the forward direction along the arrow. So, here is a way
我可以根据以前已知的姿势定义一个未知的姿势。
that I can define an unknown pose in terms of previously known poses.
我们现在得到的是某种姿势代数，只有一些简单的规则
What we’ve got now is some kind of pose algebra and there are just a few simple rules
用姿势代数。第一条规则涉及O+运算符。我可以结合两个亲戚
with a pose algebra. The first rule is concerned with the O+ operator. I can combine two relative
提出另一个相对姿势，但有一些非常重要的规则相关联
poses to get another relative pose but there are some really important rules associated
这里有所有下标。第一个规则是这两个下标，一个在上面
with all the subscripts here. The first rule is that these two subscripts, the one on the
O+运算符的任一侧必须相同。你可以把它们想象为取消
either side of the O+ operator, must be the same. And you can think of them as cancelling
出。然后，这个前导下标在表达式和下标的两边是相同的
out. Then, this leading subscript is the same on both sides of the expression and this subscript
在表达的两边是相同的。O+运算符不是可交换的
is the same on both sides of the expression. The O+ operator is not commutative and that
意味着，如果我有一个相对姿势1和一个具有相对姿势2的O+，那么，一般来说，
means that if I have a relative pose 1, and an O+ with relative pose 2, that is, in general,
不同于相对姿势2O+相对姿势1.你必须非常小心
different to relative pose 2 O+ relative pose 1. You have to be really careful about the
订单，你不能随意切换它们。另一个规则是应用O-运算符
order and you can’t arbitrarily switch them around. Another rule is that O- operator applied
相对姿势与交换前导和尾随标签相同。另一个规则
to the relative pose is the same as swapping the leading and trailing labels. Another rule
是我姿势O-相同的姿势，结果为零。它对应于没有动作，
is that I have pose O- the same pose, the result is zero. It corresponds to no motion,
没有姿势变化，我们使用符号零来表示。而且，我可以表达的另一种方式
no pose change and we use symbol zero to represent that. And, another way I can express that
是否定姿势然后将其添加到姿势，结果为零。这两个表达方式
is to negate the pose and then add it to the pose, the result is zero. These two expressions
是等价的。最后，如果我将零相对姿势添加到姿势，则不会发生任何变化。
are equivalent. Finally, if I add the zero relative pose to a pose, it makes no change.
而且，如果我从姿势中减去零相对姿势，它就不会改变。
And, if I subtract the zero relative pose from a pose, it makes no change.
这些只是我们可以应用于这些复杂姿势表达式的一些简单代数规则
These are just a few simple algebraic rules that we can apply to these complex pose expressions
这允许我们重新排列它们以确定我们想要的东西
which allows us to rearrange them to determine the things that we want in terms of the things
我们知道。有一些规则也适用于我们合并的这个点运算符
that we know. There are a few rules also that apply to this dot operator where we combine
一个带有向量的姿势。而且，我们在这里有一些适用于标签的规则。一次
a pose with a vector. And again, we have some rules that apply to the labels here. And once
再次，最里面的标签必须是相同的。然后，我们可以将它们视为取消
again, the innermost labels must be the same. And then, we can think of them as cancelling
out和领先的标签是一样的。
out and the leading labels are the same.